Contact

valurti@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/michael-reidmsn-rn-ccrn-08170121 (LinkedIn) thenclexcure.com (Company) www.patreon.com/nursemichael (Company)

Top Skills

Healthcare

Nursing

HIPAA

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Registered Nurse CCRN

Honors-Awards

Sigma Theta Tau

Publications

CliffsNotes NCLEX-RN Cram Plan

Michael Reid, MSN RN CCRN

Skilled Critical Care Nurse (CCRN), Author CliffsNotes NCLEX / HESI A2, McGraw Hill CCRN, Entrepreneur of Nursing EdTech Chicago, Illinois

Summary

Critical Care RN/MSN/CCRN specializing in acutely ill patients of both medical and surgical needs. Open heart surgery trained working with post-op coronary bypass, valve replacements, and other procedures requiring post-op in-depth care including continuous hemodynamic monitoring, arterial lines, swan ganz catheters, pharmaceutical titrations, mechanical ventilation, and management of all body systems.

Small business owner teaching upcoming nurses across the United States and Canada. Author of the CliffsNotes for the NCLEX. Author of upcoming CliffsNotes Science HESI A2. Author of upcoming McGraw Hill CCRN Review

Experience

Nursology / The NCLEX Cure
Founder / Director of Nursing Development
January 2015 - Present (5 years 6 months)
New York City, Chicago

www.thenclexcure.com www.nursology.com (in production)

Ready! Set! Inject!

I founded this company to help new nurses enter the field and succeed once they are in it. Nursing education is never easy to digest. It can often become costly and time consuming in a school and hospital setting. We provide affordable, and straight-to-the-point method of mastering tricky subjects. Our method of NCLEX teaching achieves a pass rating of 95% and is retained by hundreds of students and multiple nursing schools.

My clients include students and schools from NYU to University of Houston. I have taught students from coast to coast and in Canada.

My book for NCLEX study, The Crash Course, was recently picked up by Mifflin Harcourt for full publishing. I revamped it for their CliffsNotes style. It was publisd 9/11/2018. I am now working on my second book, HESI A2 Science, for the same publisher.

New age education for new age nurses!

CareRev Travel Critical Care Nurse

September 2019 - Present (10 months)

Chicago, Illinois, United States

Floating around Chicago to hospitals in need. With the COVID-19 crisis, much of the work I do is related to critical care complications by coronavirus. Stay safe nurses!

McGraw-Hill
Author
September 2019 - Present (10 months)
CCRN Review - currently writing

Houghton Mifflin Harcourt
Author
2018 - Present (2 years)
CliffsNotes HESI A2 Science Cram Plan - currently in editing

CliffsNotes NCLEX-RN Cram Plan uses calendars to create a specific study plan for test-takers depending on how much time they have left before they take the test. Also included is a specialized NCLEX-PN study plan, meaning that NCLEX-PN test-takers can use this book to pass their nursing exam, too! The NCLEX-RN test is taken by individuals who want to become a registered nurse; the NCLEX-PN test is taken by those who want to become a practical nurse.

Features of this plan-to-ace-the-test product include: Timed, boxed calendars for preparing to take the test—2-month study calendar, 1-month study calendar, and 1-week study calendar

- •Diagnostic test that helps test-takers pinpoint strengths and weaknesses so they can focus their review on topics in which they need the most help
- •Subject reviews that succinctly cover need-to-know topics on the tests in a list format
- •Model practice test with answers and explanations

Advocate Health Care
Registered Nurse II
May 2018 - July 2019 (1 year 3 months)
Chicago

Illinois Masonic Medical Center is a Magnet designation hospital that resides in Lakeview, Chicago. We are staffed by an interdisciplinary team of critical care specialists, trauma residents, surgical residents, mid-level providers, critical care nurses, respiratory therapists, and more.

This is the Surgical and Trauma ICU, one of the few Trauma I centers in Chicago that can accommodate the highest level of critical patient. On top of all critical surgeries (neuro, cardiovascular), trauma patients include GSW victims, stab victims, MVA's, among many others.

It is the job of all the nurses on this unit to coordinate the very difficult and specific care required to handle this exciting yet intense patient population.

Presence Health
Staff Nurse
April 2017 - May 2018 (1 year 2 months)
Greater Chicago Area

CCRN in the ICU managing a wide array of acute patient problems requiring close hemodynamic monitoring, ventilator management, medication titrations, etc.) Patient population consists of open heart surgeries, shock (septic and cardiogenic more common), COPD exacerbations, DKA Crisis, GI surgeries, acute overdoses, myocardial infarction, stroke, and more.

Johns Hopkins Hospital
Nurse Clinician
April 2014 - November 2014 (8 months)
Cardiovascular Surgical Intensive Care Unit

Northwestern Memorial Hospital Float Pool PCT January 2013 - April 2014 (1 year 4 months)

Page 3 of 4

Edward Hines VA Hospital Nurse Extern (SICU) June 2013 - August 2013 (3 months) Hines, Illinois

Howard Brown Health Center Health Information Management January 2011 - February 2012 (1 year 2 months)

Education

DePaul University
M.S, Nursing · (2012 - 2013)

Columbia College Chicago BA, Management · (2005 - 2008)

Purdue University Biology · (2003 - 2005)